Guide to the Richard Bonelli Collection
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound
- Sound recordings
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Aida. Selections IIMar.2, 1940, 1 sound disc: acetate; 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 171)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Aida. Selections IVMar.2, 1940, 1 sound disc: acetate; 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 173)
    Metropolitan Opera. Bampton, Rose
  - Lady walks. Trio Mulholland, 1 sound disc: acetate; 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 174)
  - Chopin and Wagner, 1 sound disc: acetate; 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 175)
    Chopin, Fr233;d233;ric, 1810-1849. Waltz in A flat -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Walkürenritt. Philadelphia Orchestra. Ormandy, Eugene, 1899-1985, conductor
  - Spoiled child, 1 sound disc: acetate; 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 176)
    Mead, Grace
  - Turkey in the strawOct. 24, 1938, 1 sound disc: acetate; 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 177)
    Arranged by Kay Kellogg. Piano: Kellogg, Kay and Munger Mollie
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello, selections and Ave Maria, 1 sound disc: acetate; 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 178)
    Rethberg, Elisabeth, 1894-1976, voice. Ormandy, Eugene, 1899-1985, conductor
  - Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Madama Butterfly, selections, 1 sound disc: Presto recording blank. Aluminium substrate; 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 179)
    Moore, Grace, 1898-1947
  - Amapola and When I have sung my songsFeb.3, 1937, 1 sound disc: Presto recording blank. Aluminium substrate; 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 180)
    Chesterfield hour (Radio program) Martini, singer -- Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962, singer
  - Lord, I wanna be, 1 sound disc acetate: 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 181)
    Franklyn, Kelly, singer
  - Bunny, 1 sound disc acetate: 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 182)
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Wesendonck-Lieder. Träume Mar. 1928, 1 sound disc acetate: 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 183)
    Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962, singer
  - Thomas, Ambroise, 1811-1896. Mignon. Overture, trio Act II Mar. 13, 1937, 1 sound disc acetate: 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 184)
    Metropolitan Opera orchestra. Pelletier, Wilfrid, 1896-1982, conductor
  - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Elektra. Parts I and II, 1 sound disc acetate: 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 185)
  - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Elektra. Parts III and IV, 1 sound disc acetate: 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 186)
  - Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Faust. Selections Jan. 31, 1937, 1 sound disc Presto recording blank. Aluminium substrate: 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 187)
  - King David. Selections, 1 sound disc acetate: 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 188)
  - Kiss me again, 1 sound disc acetate: 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 189)
    Bampton, Rose, singer
  - Templeton I, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 190)
  - Templeton II, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 191)
  - Templeton IIIAug.10, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 192)
  - Templeton IV, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 193)
  - Templeton VAug.15, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #1. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 194)
  - Test record for cutting needle, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 195)
  - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Manon, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 196)
    Sayão, Bidú, soprano; Rayner, Sidney, 1895-1981, tenor; Baromeo, Chase, bass
  - Mascagni and Chopin, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 197)
    Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. Cavalleria rusticana. Voi lo sapete. Cigna, Gina, 1900-, soprano. With annotation "very good record" -- Chopin, Fr233;d233;ric, 1810-1849. Étude, piano, A? major and F major. Hess, Myra, Dame, 1890-1965, piano
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Aïda. Selections, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 198)
    Metropolitan Opera. Cigna, Gina, 1900-, soprano and Castagna, Bruna, alto
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Siegfried. Selections, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 199)
    Metropolitan Opera. Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962, sopran and Melchior, Lauritz, tenor
  - Puccini and Wagner, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 200)
    Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Madama Butterfly. Selections. Moore, Grace, 1898-1947, soprano -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Parsifal. Selections
  - Buxtehude and WagnerMar. 28, 1936, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 201)
    Philadelphia Orchestra. Ormandy, Eugene, 1899-1985, conductor. Buxtehude, Dietrich, 1637-1707. Passacaglia -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Meistersinger von Nürnberg. Tanz der Lehrbuben.
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Walkürenritt; Rheingold. Selections, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 202)
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Lohengrin. Part I, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 203)
    Metropolitan Opera. Abravanel, Maurice, 1903-1993, conductor. Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962, soprano; Maison, Ren233;, 1895-1962, tenor; Hoffmann, ? bass
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Lohengrin. Part II, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 204)
    Metropolitan Opera. Abravanel, Maurice, 1903-1993, conductor
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Lohengrin. Part III, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 205)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Trovatore. Selection, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 206)
    Lazzari, Virgilio, 1887-1953, bass
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Feuerzauber; Tristan und Isolde. Prelude, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 207)
  - Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953. Peter and the wolf. Part IFeb. 28, 1941, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 208)
    Philadelphia Orchestra. Ormandy, Eugene, 1899-1985, conductor
  - Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953. Peter and the wolf. Part IIFeb. 28, 1941, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 209)
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Lohengrin. Einsam in trüben Tagen; Duet, 1 sound disc acetate: 12 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 210)
    Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962, soprano; Branzell, Karin, 1891-1974, alto
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Parsifal. Act III, 1 sound disc acetate: 10 in. Set of discs originally in tin box #2. Original order of discs kept (Box 45, Folder 211)
    New York Philharmonic.
- Testimonials and awards; posters and snakes
  - Honor Award 1939, wood base with metal code of arms (Othertype 41, Folder 1)
  - Junta Para la Concesión del Título Honorífico de Excmo. Señor. Santa Barbara.Aug.16, 1948 (Othertype 41, Folder 2)
  - A Testimonial of AppreciationMay 19, 1955, Red, hard cover handmade book binding. Caligraphy from the Chicago Scriptorium (Othertype 41, Folder 3)
    From Bonelli's students in Philadelphia
  - AGMA Annual Merit AwardFeb.15, 1965 (Othertype 41, Folder 4)
  - W. Colston Leigh management promotional posters, mounted on cardboard (Othertype 41, Folder 1)
  - "Happy Birthday to Richard Bonelli" Joanie and Bob, Watercolor and pen drawing on cardboard (Othertype 41, Folder 2)
- News clippings
  - Clippings from 1916-1929 (Box 42)
  - Clippings from 1930-1986 (Box 43)
- Miscellany
  - Leather fold with inscription "Met Debut 1932" (Othertype 41, Folder 14.1)
    Originally contained newspaper clippings
  - One loose bookpage of Emerson's Essays (annotated) (Othertype 41, Folder 14.2)
  - Letterhead paper of Richard Bonelli (Othertype 41, Folder 14.3)
  - Opera Announcements (snakes), In very delicate condition. Do not handle (Othertype 44, Folder 14.4)
    Snakes in oversize packet. Snake fragments in envelope 14.4, box 41.